In this video we're going to talk about type checking in cool. Thus far, we've
在这段视频中，我们将讨论如何在酷中进行类型签入。到目前为止，我们已经
seen two examples of formal notation used to specify parts of a compiler. Regular
查看了用于指定编译器各部分的两个形式表示法示例。常规
expressions were used in lexical analysis, and context free grammars which we used in
表达式用在词法分析中，上下文无关文法用在
parsing. It turns out that there's another formalism which has gained widespread
正在解析。原来，还有另一种形式主义，它得到了广泛的支持
acceptance in type checking, and that's logical rules of inference. If-else rules
类型检查中的接受，这是推理的逻辑规则。If-Else规则
are logical statements that have the form; if some hypothesis is true then some
是具有以下形式的逻辑语句；如果某些假设为真，则某些
conclusion is true. So, if-else rules are implication statements that some
结论是正确的。因此，IF-ELSE规则是一些隐含语句
hypothesis implies some conclusion And in the particular case of type checking an
假设隐含了一些结论，在类型检查的特定情况下，
example or typical kind of reasoning that we see in type checking is that if a
我们在类型检查中看到的示例或典型类型的推理是，如果
couple of expressions have certain types then some other expression is guaranteed
几个表达式具有特定的类型，则保证另一个表达式
to have a certain type. And so clearly that the type checking statement here is
拥有某种类型。很明显，这里的类型检查语句是
an example of an inference rule. An inference rule notation is just a compact
推理规则的示例。推理规则符号只是紧凑的
way of encoding these kinds of if then statements. Now if you haven't seen this
这类IF THEN语句的编码方式。如果你还没有看过这个
notation before, it will be unfamiliar, but actually it's quite easy to read with
以前的符号，它可能不熟悉，但实际上它很容易阅读
practice And we'll start with a very simple system and gradually add features.
练习之后，我们将从一个非常简单的系统开始，然后逐步添加功能。
So we'll use a logical conjunction for the English word and, and implication for the
因此，我们将对英语单词AND使用逻辑连接词，对
English word if and then. And now, one special thing, the string x colon t is
英语单词IF和THEN。现在，有一件特别的事，字符串x冒号t是
read that x has type t. So this is logical assertion saying that x has a particular
读一下x的类型是t，所以这是逻辑断言，说x有一个特殊的
type. So now consider the following very simple type rule. If E one has type int,
键入。因此，现在考虑以下非常简单的类型规则。如果E 1具有INT类型，
and E two has type int, then E one plus E two also has type int. And we could just
E 2是int类型，那么E 1加E 2也是int类型。我们可以干脆
take the definitions we gave on the previous slide and just gradually reduce
采用我们在上一张幻灯片中给出的定义，然后逐步减少
this to a mathematical statement. So, for example, we can replace the if then with
这可以归结为一个数学陈述。例如，我们可以将IF THEN替换为
an implication. And we can replace the word and with a conjunction. And now we
一种暗示。我们可以用连词代替and这个词。现在我们
just have these has type statements, alright? And we had a notation for that,
只要有这些HAS类型语句就行了，好吗？我们对此有一个记号，
and we wind up with this purely mathematical statement that, which says
我们最终得到了这个纯粹的数学陈述，它说
exactly the same thing. That if E1 has type int and E2 has type int, that implies
完全一样的事情。如果E1有INT类型，E2有INT类型，这意味着
that E1 + E2 has type int. And notice that, that statement that we just wrote
E1+E2的类型是int。注意，我们刚才写的那个声明
out is a special case of an inference rule. It's a bunch of hypothesis conjoined
OUT是推理规则的特例。这是一堆连结在一起的假设
together and implies some conclusion. The traditional notation for inference rules
并暗示了一些结论。推理规则的传统表示法
is given here. The hypotheses are written about the horizontal line, and the
是在这里给出的。假设是关于水平线的，而
conclusion is written below. And it means exactly the same thing as what we had on
结论写在下面。它的意思和我们穿的完全一样
the previous slide. Mainly that if all the things above the horizontal line are true.
上一张幻灯片。主要是如果水平线上的所有东西都是真的。
These are all the hypotheses, then the thing below. The horizontal line can be
这些都是假设，然后是下面的事情。水平线可以是
concluded to be true. And there's one piece of new notation here. This is the
断定是真的。这里有一个新的符号。这是
turnstiles that are used for the hypotheses and the conclusion. And the
用于假设和结论的旋转门。以及
turnstile is read, it is provable that. And what this means is that we're just
旋转栅门是读过的，这是可以证明的。这意味着我们只是
going to say explicitly. That something is provable in the system of rules that we're
我要明确地说。在我们所处的规则体系中有些东西是可以证明的
defining. So the way you would read this is that if it's provable that all these
定义。所以你解读这个的方式是，如果所有这些都是可以证明的
hypotheses are true. So, if it's provable the first hypothesis is true, all the
假设是正确的。所以，如果第一个假设是真的，那么所有的
middle hypotheses, and if it's improvable, if it's provable the last hypothesis is
中间假设，如果它是可以改进的，如果它是可证明的，那么最后一个假设是
true. Then it is provable that the conclusion is true And cool type rules are
没错。那么可以证明结论是真的，酷的类型规则是
going to have. The following kinds of hypothesis and conclusions we're going to
将会有。我们要做的假设和结论有以下几种
prove, within the system, that some expression has a particular type. So with
在系统中证明某个表达式具有特定类型。所以有了
those definitions out of the way we actually have enough to write at least a
我们实际上有足够的定义来编写至少一个
few simple type rules. So, if I integer literally if it's an integer class
几个简单的类型规则。因此，如果I按字面意义整型，如果它是一个整型类
interfering in my program then this rules says it is provable that I has type ENT.
干扰我的程序，那么这个规则说我有ENT类型是可以证明的。
So every integer constant has type ENT. And here's the rule for add written out
所以每个整数常量都有ENT类型。下面是添加写出的规则
now in the [inaudible] rule notation. If it's provable then that E1 has type int
现在用[听不见的]规则符号。如果它是可证明，则E1具有INT类型
and is provable that E2 has type ENT. Then it is provable that E1 plus E2 has type
可以证明E2具有ENT型。那么就可以证明E1+E2是有类型的
ENT. So notice that these rules give templates for describing how to type
请进。请注意，这些规则提供了描述如何键入的模板
integers and expressions. The rule for integer constants just use a generic
整数和表达式。整数常量规则仅使用泛型
integer i. It didn't give a separate rule for every possible integer, and the rule
整数i。它没有为每个可能的整数给出单独的规则，而规则
for plus used expressions e one and e two. It didn't tell you what particular
用于加号使用的表达式e1和e2。它没有告诉你具体是什么
expressions they were. It just said give me any expression e one, any expressions e
他们的表情是。它只是说给我任何表情e一，任何表情e
one and e two that have type int. And so we can plug any expressions we want in
类型为int的1和e 2。所以我们可以插入任何我们想要的表达式
that satisfy the hypotheses, and then we can produce a complete typing for actual
满足假设，然后我们就可以为Actual生成一个完整的类型
expressions. So as a concrete example, let's show that one plus two has type ent.
表情。作为一个具体的例子，让我们展示一下1加2的类型为ent。
So we want to type the expression one plus two, and since we know the rule for add
所以我们想键入表达式1+2，因为我们知道加法的规则
that means we need to construct a proof of the type of the number one, and a proof of
这意味着我们需要构造数字1的类型的证明，以及数字1的类型的证明
the type of the number two. And we have a rule for dealing with integer classes,
数字2的类型。我们有一个处理整数类的规则，
mainly we can prove because one is an integer class that has type ent, and we
我们可以证明的主要原因是，其中一个是类型为ent的整数类，而我们
can prove that two is type ent, and then now we have the two hypothesis we need for
可以证明二是ENT型的，那么现在我们就有了我们需要的两个假设
the sum expression and we can prove that one plus two has type ent. So, an
求和表达式，我们可以证明一加二具有ENT型。所以，一个
important property of any reasonable type system is that it be sound. And sound is
任何合理类型系统的重要属性都是健全的。而声音是
here is a correctness condition. What we want is whatever the type system can prove
这里有一个正确的条件。我们需要的是类型系统能证明的任何东西
that some expression has the type systems has a particular type T. The if I actually
某些表达式的类型系统具有特定的类型T。如果我实际上
run that program. If I take E and I execute it on the computer the value that
运行那个程序。如果我取E并在计算机上执行它，
it returns, the value that comes after running E in fact has the type predicted
它返回，则运行E之后的值实际上具有预测的类型
by the type system. So, if the type system It is able to give types of things that
通过类型系统。因此，如果类型系统能够给出
actually reflect what kind of value you get when you run the program then we say
实际反映您在运行程序时获得的价值，然后我们说
that the type system is sound. Now clearly we only want sound rules but some sound
打字系统是健全的。现在很明显，我们只想要健全的规则，但也要一些健全的
rules are actually quite a bit better than others, so for example. If I have an
例如，规则实际上比其他规则要好得多。如果我有一个
integer literal And I want to give it a type, while we, we, I showed you the best
整型文字，我想给它一个类型，而我们，我们，我给你们展示了最好的
possible rule before where we said that [inaudible] has type [inaudible] But it
可能的规则之前我们说过[听不见]有类型[听不见]但它
would also be correct, just not very precise to say that has [inaudible] has
也会是正确的，只是不太准确地说有[听不见]有
type object. Certainly if I evaluate an integer I will get back an object because
键入Object。当然，如果我计算一个整数，我会得到一个对象，因为
every integer in , is also an object But this isn't all that useful because now I
中的每个整数也是一个对象，但这不是很有用，因为现在我
can't do any of the integer operations And so there are lots of different sound
我不能做任何整数运算，所以有很多不同的声音
rules, there's not just one unique rule for any given [inaudible] expression that
规则，对于任何给定的[听不见的]表达式，不只有一条唯一的规则
will be sound, but some of them are better than others, and in the case of integer
将是健全的，但它们中的一些比其他的要好，并且在整数的情况下
literals the one we really want. Literal has type it because that is the most
字面意思就是我们真正想要的。文本类型为它，因为这是最多的
specific type that we can give to that type of program.
我们可以为该类型的程序指定的特定类型。